[Music]
foreign
automation tutorial
as you all know I've already published
14 YouTube lessons
covering different concepts of tricent
testoster by using latest version 16.
so this is our 15th lesson where I'm
gonna teach you how to apply the value
range and how can you rescan the
controls that are required to automate
your test Case by using Tasker and also
how can you perform module merge and why
do we need to perform module much
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay so what is our agenda
the first one is
rescan existing modules
so if you want to reuse the modules or
remap the controls that can no longer be
identified then it's very very important
for us to rescan the modules
and then
manage value range column
so how can we do that and why do we need
you can go to your module attribute
level and add values to the value range
column so these values added there then
creates a list or the drop down list
for the attributes that can be chosen
from the drop down so basically whatever
the values that you define in the value
range
those values can be used in this case as
a test data attributes so basically I'm
defining the test data
in the module itself so that when I'm
creating or when I am automating the
test cases I can simply use the module
and then I can simply select the test
data that I required from the drop down
so you need not to remember the test
data basically so let's say you have
some coupon codes to apply so you will
have some prerequisite coupon codes
right so you need not to remember all
these coupon codes you simply capture
these in the value range of your
particular module attribute and then the
same coupon codes you can use in the
test cases so I'm going to teach you how
can you manage value range shortly okay
and then module merge so this allows you
to combine two modules together
if
attributes are duplicated in the modules
you can also link this attribute and
decide how you want to identify them so
when you are merging your modules right
if there are some duplicate attributes
you can simply decide which attribute to
be used and then which attributes can be
merged right so now let's jump onto the
system and see how can we perform
rescanning and then how can you use the
value range column and then how can you
perform merge module okay so now let's
jump onto the system
okay so this is my task car right
um so let's navigate to modules so our
first agenda item is understand rescan
existing modules okay so for that let's
navigate to module and then webshop
under webshop you have checkout process
under checkout process exercise 18
rescan value range module merge okay
under this
select the module webshop shopping cart
rescale
okay this module is same as the earlier
module that we used
in our previous videos while automating
our test cases okay shopping cart
related scenario right so we have used
the same module
to automate our test case and this also
same so it suggests a duplicate of these
two so I just want to show you how can
we rescan and then merge these two
shopping carts once we rescan
why I only need to rescan let me explain
why do I need to rescan the module okay
so what is the scenario that we already
discussed earlier we generally go to
as a user you logged into shopping
portal go to apparel instant shows right
so I have already published almost like
13 YouTube videos so I have explained
everything about webshop in my previous
videos and
we keep on
using this website in every video okay
so now let's go to Blue Jeans
and here we are going to add the
quantity of 25
add to cart
go to shopping cart and here till date
what we did we have just agreed to it
and checked out right but
this time
what if I need to apply a discount code
or what if if I need to apply gift card
code so that I'll get the discount
so that means I need to add or what if
if I need to update the shopping cart
right so for that I need to add all the
controls update shopping cart enter
coupon code apply coupon right this edit
box add gift card so I need to add all
these controls to my previous module
earlier we just added checkout
I agree right and this probably I think
this quantity that's it
so now I need to add these additional
controls
so for that the rescan is useful okay
so when you rescan an existing module
you should open the page where you want
to scan or where you want to capture the
additional controls in the existing
module okay you need to leave the Page
open
and then go back to your existing module
and right click and select rescan
as soon as you select rescan
the xcan window will open
and then it will redirect you to the
same page
where you
capture the controls earlier
okay
so here it is opening the xcan now
and then it redirects you to the page
which we already opened okay
so you need not to select the page that
you want to scan it automatically
redirects you okay
okay so if you see here
your page is open
and your shopping cart is there okay
so if you see here
all these three controls are already
added now I need to add additional
controls right
for that click on select on screen
and then
add
update shopping cart button
add discount coupon code edit box
add apply coupon button
add gift quantity box
add
gift card button and let's rename some
of the controls
for discount coupon code
name this as enter
discount
coupon
code
for gift card
enter
gift card code
okay
so we rename this controls the controls
and now you can
let me see if I'm missing anything
that's it you can Simply Save
and then
close
so if you go back it automatically
redirects you to the
module if you see here earlier there are
only three controls right so now I can
see all the controls that I just now
added
okay
so now
the module got updated
okay
so now let's say
see because I have created a new module
with additional controls
earlier I have another module I created
for same shopping cart additional uh
sorry another module with limited
controls right limited controls only
these which we used earlier now I have
another duplicate shopping cart module
with some additional controls so now if
you want to merge these two
modules our next agenda is merging
merge modules right
to merge the modules what should we do
so before merging the modules let us
understand
manage value range column okay
so if you go here under
coupon code let me just rename this okay
under enter discount coupon code
so when you enter the discount coupon
code I think we missed one more thing
actually here another thing is let me
I missed two scan another code another
control what is that let me tell you
so let me apply some discount coupon
code here okay let me apply discount
coupon code apply code so as soon as I
click on apply code the coupon code was
applied so this success message comes on
the screen I want to capture this also
let me rescan this again
rescan
rescan the module
so now
as we did earlier it automatically
redirects you to the same page by
opening your xcan
see this is your xcan window
now I need to add that text box
successful text box okay so let's go
here
filter to the next
select on screen
I want to add this
div
so let's rename this
the coupon code
oh sorry
applied message
coupon code applied message
okay
so now let's save this now
and then close it so as soon as you
close so now you see there is a coupon
code applied message a new one is there
okay
so now when
if you see here
now let me understand let me tell you
how to add a value range column
so when you are applying the coupon code
there are different types of coupon
codes if you see this coupon code got me
five dollars of discount let's say if I
want to apply this coupon code what is
this one second coupon code okay
percentage total
if I apply this coupon code
it is giving me a discount of 2.5
dollars so you have several coupon codes
that you can test right
so do I need to remember all these
coupon codes no you need not to remember
when you are automating your test cases
you need not to remember all these
different types of coupon codes instead
you can basically Define these coupon
codes as an attributes
for your module control for your control
so this is my control enter discount
coupon code here
I can
specify these coupon codes as attributes
how just copy these coupon codes
go to here
and enter all these coupon codes you
need to enter all these I mean copy and
paste so basically I'm entering coupon
codes without spaces see this is my
coupon code separate with semicolon no
space and second coupon code separate
with semicolon no space
that's it and save this
so what it will do
when you map this module so in my
previous uh videos I already showed you
how to automate our how to map your
module to the test case right when you
automate your test cases you use modules
drag and drop to the test case right
so when you drag and drop this coupon
code
once you go to let's say hey let me go
to the test case one of the test case
so I don't have coupon code anyway here
so what I can do in the test case
attribute when I open my test case here
let's assume this is one my edit box for
example okay let me
here
here I'm entering value here you can
directly see the drop down values of
those coupon codes
you can directly set the coupon code
apart from click double click and right
click you can also see these values what
these coupon code values so here
directly you can select the coupon code
so that that coupon code will be entered
into the edit box while running the test
case
so it's very important and it really
makes
your automation very easy it reduces lot
of time
okay so basically the test data you are
defining as an attribute under module
itself under
column called value range
okay
so that is the advantage of your value
range that's how you can manage your
value range
now so now let's go back to merge
modules okay as I told you earlier we
created a new module with these
additional controls whereas we have used
the same module here earlier with
limited controls so now I have shopping
cart modules two shopping cart modules
correct which are duplicate I need not
to manage these two shopping cart models
so now I need to merge these two
shopping cart models you need to select
the modules
that you would like to merge okay I have
selected these two modules
and then on top ribbon uh there is an
option called
module merge modules click on merge
modules
so as soon as you click on merge modules
a merge module assistant will open
here so self there is one conflict here
attribute has conflict resolve conflict
okay here self healing data I need not
to have let me just delete this okay so
and then if you see
these are all the additional if you see
shopping cart product check out terms of
service add gift cards so basically
these are all the controls and these are
all my additional controls right so
these are all uniquely identified and
and my Target module so Target module is
the module that is going to remind and
your Source module is the module that is
going to delete once we merge the
modules if you see here now all those
all these modules are uniquely
identified and mapped to each other
right so now you can simply click on
merge okay if there is any conflict you
can
uh basically resolve the conflicts by
linking okay if you see all these are
linked properly
and you can simply okay let me
I think check out let's see
checkout is there
okay this one link checkout
I can link check out to checkout
okay
um
okay it says
okay so that way you can link if I want
to link
uh terms of service right you can simply
select this so these two got linked so
this way you can link the properties
and then merge the modules okay so in
this case for in my case because my
target module has the updated module
properties I want to keep only target
modules okay that's why I'm gonna click
merge as soon as I click on merge it
merges all your properties
and it keeps your target if you see here
the source module will be deleted
okay
so done
close it if you see here you don't have
another shopping cart module here I have
only one shopping cart module now rename
this
as shopping cart
that's it so now
my shopping cart
module is only one module with all my
controls right
so hope you all understand the concepts
of
rescan existing module why we are
rescanning and how can you manage the
value range column
in your module at attribute level right
that means test data can be managed as
in attributes so that you can use them
in test case section as a drop down
values you simply pick up those uh the
test data from the drop down values
right and then how can you merge the
modules
okay hope you all understand the
concepts very well these are all really
very very important Concepts while
automating your test cases if you have
any queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries
thank you hope you all understand how to
apply the value range how can you
perform rescanning of your modules or
rescanning of your controls and then how
can you perform module merge
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
[Music]